In this short video, I'm going
to demonstrate how you can take a
screen print and insert that into
a document, save that document
and then open it at a later date.
A screen print is basically
a snapshot of whatever is on
the screen at that given time.
So if you press the print screen button,
it would take a photograph and then
that would be stored onto the clipboard.
As you work through the course, you'll
be required to provide several screen
prints in each assessment document to
evidence that you have used a specific
tool or carried out a specific task.
So to take a screen print.
You would need to use the print
screen button, and this will be
labeled P R T S C on your keyboard.
If you are using a more modern laptop, you
may find that you have to hold down the
fn to activate the print screen button.
So to demonstrate the print screen,
I'm going to open up a folder, which
contains my Word processing materials.
And I'm going to take a  snapshot of
that, a print screen of that folder.
So what I need to do is I'm going
to hold down the alt key and
press the print screen button.
Now nothing would appear to have happened,
but a snapshot has been taken and
that has been stored on the clipboard.
So if I now go to a Word document and
I'll just open a blank word document.
And then I can select paste or use
the shortcut key Control and V.
As you can see, that has then pasted
the snapshot into the Word document.
So now I have satisfied that
I have the screen print in the
document, and I'm happy with that.
I'll go to File and then Save As.
I want to save  that into
my word processing folder.
So navigate to the folder.
And then give it the name screenprint
and then save that into that folder.
Then if I wanted to open it again
I would just access the folder,
double click on the screen print,
and that would bring that up.
As I say, you will be required to complete
several screen prints for each assessment.
Another thing to bear in mind
is that if you're asked to take
a screen print to show that
everything that is in the documents.
So if you have a three-page document,
you will find it beneficial to zoom
out, which will then allow if you had
more than one page, it will actually
allow you still to take just the
one screen print to show everything
that is actually on the three pages.